Lewis Kavinga Muema

CONSTRUCTION PROJECT MANAGER

kavingair@gmail.com

+25471516789 | https://lewismuema.github.io/ Voi- Taita Taveta

SUMMARY STATEMENT

Experienced graduate construction project manager with three years of experience in the construction industry delivering projects. Collaborative team player with a strong focus on productivity, attention to detail, and client satisfaction. Proficient in using project management tools, techniques and software to ensure timely delivery of projects, within projected budget and with the required standards.

EXPERIENCE

April 2024- Present

Site Surveyor, Proposed Fanaka Aluminum Plant – Athi River, Machakos County

- Completed setting out of three warehouses and servants' quarter using Total Station Machine.
- Marking out levels at required points using dumpy level so as to guide craftsmen.
- Conveying the Project Manager's instructions and interpreting drawings to subcontractors, foremen and craftsmen and following up on them.
- Controlling quality of construction works by ensuring formwork and steelworks are as required before concreting, supervising concreting to ensure the correct slump, sufficient vibration and stability of formwork is maintained all through.
- Supervision of excavation works ensuring it is done precisely in the marked area, to the correct depth, ensuring occupational safety and maintaining maximum productivity of machinery whilst monitoring for underground utilities.
- Structural detailing of drawings and translating drawings from Mandarin to English so as to be easily understandable by subcontractors, foremen and crastsmen.

January 2023 - February 2024

Construction Management Trainee, Chawucha Holdings – Voi, Taita Taveta County

- Oversaw project scope, timeline and budget ensuring coordinated and successful completion of 4+ residential and infrastructure projects.
- Mitigated high project costs by reviewing the existing material procurement procedures and efficiently managing a team of 60+ workers.
- Monitored project progress and effectively communicated with clients and stakeholders.
- Devised a solution to solve the challenge of high rate of worker absenteeism in the beginning of the week.
- Identified potential project schedule delays and facilitated intervention where possible.

July 2022- December 2022

Draftsperson, China Ghezhouba Group Company – Wote, Makueni County

- Produced detailed technical drawings and 3D models for critical structural components, including spillways, intake structures, and powerhouse foundations, ensuring precision and adherence to engineering specifications.
- Collaborated with civil and structural engineers to interpret complex design requirements, incorporating hydrological and geotechnical data.
- Coordinated with site engineers and construction managers to address design modifications and resolve technical issues, enhancing the efficiency and quality of construction activities.
- Conducted material take-offs and quantity estimations for reinforced concrete, steel reinforcements, and other construction materials.

August - November 2021

Construction Management Attaché, Jedi General Contractors Ltd – Voi, Taita Taveta County

- Evaluated productivity of workers on site ensuring adherence to time and budget.
- Assisted in project quality control on site ensuring compliance to specifications.
- Periodically presented site progress reports ensuring the client and company administration are adequately informed on the project progress.

EDUCATION

September 2018 – October 2022

Bachelor of Technology in Construction and Property Management, Kirinyaga University Courses included Construction Technology, Structures, Measurement of Civil Works, Project Management, Project Monitoring and Evaluation and Computer-Aided Design (CAD).

SKILLS

Site management Microsoft Project **Programming** Project quality control PlanSwift Teamwork Risk management Microsoft Excel Leadership **Project scheduling AutoCAD** Communication **Budgeting** ArchiCAD **Problem Solving** Setting out Safety Compliance Revit

ASSOCIATIONS AND CERTIFICATIONS

• Association of Construction Managers of Kenya (ACMK): Technician Member.

Membership Number: T005

- Global Consultants in Safety, Health and Environment: Occupational Safety & Health Certification Certification Number: OSH/10853/24
 - Global Consultants in Safety, Health and Environment:

Certification Number: FA/11163/24

REFERENCES

References available upon request.